Seattle, USA manugupt1@gmail.com

Manu Gupta

linkedin.com/in/manugupt1 github.com/manugupt1

My interests lie in working with open source technologies and contributing to open source long term. I am a maintainer of Athens, a proxy for managing Go modules. I have made contributions to Kubernetes, Moby and Linux Kernel fixing long-term bugs. I also started the GSoC program for openSUSE Linux and served as a board member in the past.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure

Jan 2022-Present

Resource Manager team

Seattle, USA

• Improved CI build times by 100% which increased team's development and release velocity.

Software Engineer II

Amazon Web Services

Dec 2018-Dec 2021

Snowball, ECS Fargate, Kubernetes EKS

Seattle, USA

- Led a team of 4 developers, designed and implemented a set of APIs to manage Snowcone lifecycle management, security assets and shipment as part of Snowcone GA.
- Implemented AWS IAM on Snowball and its corresponding services allowing creation of users and authorization via IAM policies to enable multi-tenancy.
- Implemented feature to allow customers to configure permissions for their ephemeral volumes on ECS Fargate allowing them to improve their security posture and achieve compliance goals.
- Dived deep into ECS Fargate task failure metrics and implemented fixes to decrease ECS task launch failure rates from 1% to under 0.02%.
- Decreased pod launch times on Kubernetes by 4x by detecting mountpoints faster in Linux Kernel 5.10+.
- Implemented and reviewed threat models, designs and patches for ECS and Snowball to minimize security risks.

Software Developer

Genomenon

March 2016 - Dec 2018

Ann Arbor, USA

- Implemented different subscription tiers of Mastermind (SaaS offering) increasing user growth.
- Implemented advanced search capability on Mastermind by writing Elastic search queries and APIs for customers.

Application Engineer

University of Michigan

Sept 2014 - March 2016

Ann Arbor, USA

• Implemented a data-warehouse to store research results in PostgreSQL that enabled bioinformaticians to correlate clinical and genomic data from a single store.

Software Developer

Samsung Electronics

Jan 2012 - Aug 2014

Noida, India

- Improved battery life by 5% & device performance by 10% by optimizing the display stack across various Android versions (Honeycomb to Kitkat) for low cost (sold under 200\$) phone models.
- Launched Galaxy Core 2 with premium display features for low-income markets, making it the only smartphone priced below 150\$ on GSMArena's top 10 trending smartphones for 8 months.

Education and Certifications

• M.Sc. Information Science, University of Michigan, USA.

2014-2016

B.E Computer Science, Manipal Institute of Technology, India.

2008-2012